Spooks: The Greater Good is a thriller, action film directed by Bharat Nalluri.
During a handover to the head of counter-terrorism of MI5,
Harry Pearce, a terrorist escapes custody.
When Harry disappears soon after, his protégé is tasked with finding out what happened as an
impending attack on London looms, and eventually uncovers a deadly conspiracy.
Harry Pearce, played by Peter Firth.
Will Holloway, played by Kit Harington.
Adem Qasim, played by Elyes Gabel.
Geraldine Maltby, played by Jennifer Ehle.
Oliver Mace, played by Tim McInnerny.
June Keaton, played by Tuppence Middleton.
Spooks: The Greater Good (known as MI-5 in some countries) is a 2015 British spy film,
continuing from the 2002–2011 British television spy series Spooks.
Jonathan Brackley and Sam Vincent wrote the
script, with Bharat Nalluri directing.
Peter Firth reprises his role as Harry Pearce, who
appeared in all ten series of the programme.
Also returning from the TV series are Tim McInnerny as Oliver Mace, Lara Pulver as Erin
Watts, Hugh Simon as Malcolm Wynn-Jones, and Geoffrey Streatfeild as Calum Reed.
Kit Harington and Jennifer Ehle star as new characters in leading roles.
The film was released on 8 May 2015.
Upon its release, it received generally mixed reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of corruption, escape, police, explosive, kidnapping.
The tone is intense.